Guide to the Adele C. Brockoff Correspondence
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Adele C. Brockoff Correspondence,
1946-1981.
Brockhoff, Adele C.
0.5 linear ft (29 items in 1 box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079484
Biographic note
Scope and Content
Correspondence including twenty letters from Helen Keller and her companion Polly Thomson, letters from Pauline Hemingway and her son Patrick M. Hemingway, from Patricia Nixon, Nancy Reagan, and from Harry Emerson Fosdick. These are all of a personal nature. There are also several books by and about Helen Keller and by Ernest Hemingway, some of which are first editions and some inscribe by the author.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series
Series I: Manuscripts
Series II: Books
Subjects
Thomson, Polly.; Hemingway, Pauline.; Hemingway, Patrick M.; Nixon, Pat, 1912-1993.; Reagan, Nancy, 1923-; Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1878-1969.; Keller, Helen, 1880-1968.; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961.; Autographs.
Acquisition
1984 M-84 Brockhoff, Adele C. Gift
Gift of Adele C. Brockhoff, 1984.
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - Fosdick. Harry Emerson. New York. 27 Jan 1953. To Adele C. Brockhott. t.1.s. 1p. (with t.copy of letter from Helen Keller to Fosdick. 18 Feb 1953. and t.copy of his reply, 27 Feb 1953)
  - Hemingway. Patrick M. and Henriette Broy1es Hemingway (Mrs. Patrick M.) East Africa [ca.1952) To Adele C. Brockhofa.l.s. (in the hand of Mrs. Hemingway)
  - Hemingway. Pauine Pfeitter (Mrs. Ernest) Key West, Fla., 2 June 1951 & [n.d.], To Adele C. Brockhoff, 1 a.l.s., 3 t.l.s.
  - Keller, Helen. Seattle. 27 May 1946. To Gustevus A. Pfeitter. t.1.s., 2p.
  - -------. Westport. Conn. 1949 -1957. To Adela C. Brockhof1 a.1.s., 7 t.l.s.
  - -------. [Westport. Conn.) Christmas 1949 -1950. To [Adela C. Brockhoff) 2 p.c.s. (2 Christmas cards, signed by Miss Keller and Polly Thompson)
  - Nixon. Patricia Ryan (Mrs Richard N.) Washington, 12 July 1972. To Adela C. Brockhoff t.1.s, 1p. (with envelope)
  - Reagan, Nancy (Mrs Ronald) Washington, 16 November 1981. To Adela C. Brockhoft.1.s., 1p.
  - Thompson, Polly. Westport, Conn., 1952 - 1957 & n.d. To Adela C. Brockhof8 a.1.s. (written on behalf and signed for Helen Keller and herself)
  - Thompson, Polly. n.p., n.d. To Adele C. Brockhofa.1.s., 1.p. (With envelope; removed from Helen Keller, My Religion, 1927)
- Series II: Books (Catalogued in the Rare Book Collection)
  - Braddy, Nella. Anne Sullivan Macy: the story behind Helen Keller. Garden City: Doubleday, 1934. Inscribed to Adele C. Brockhoff abd signed by Helen Keller, Anne Sullivan and Polly Thomson
  - Hemingway, Ernest. For whom the bell tolls. New York: Scribner’s, 1940. First edition, first printing. Inscribed to Adele C. Brockhoff and signed by the author
  - -------. Winner take nothing. New York: Seribner’s, 1933. Signed by the author.
  - Keller, Helen. Let us have faith. New York: Doubleday, 1940. First edition. Inscribed to Adele C. Brockhoff and signed by the author. Dec 1940. With a.n. to Miss Brockhoff by Gustavus A. Pfeifter, 28 July 1942
  - -------. My religion. Garden City: Doubleday, 1927
  - -------. Teacher: Anne Sullivan Macy. A tribute by the foster-child of her mind. Introduction by Nella Braddy Henney. Garden City: Doubleday, 1955. First edition.